Heiwa Fansubs Presents:
Great Detective Conan
Challenge to Kudo Shin'ichi
Shin'ichi!
Ran! Damn!
Ran!
Shin'ichi!
Type in the password once more.
Shin'ichi?
Ran, are you okay?
Shin'ichi!
Shin'ichi, save me!
Save me...
Stop!
You thought you could run away from me?
Stop! Don't come near me!
You thought you'd make a fool of me!?
You deceived me, you rascal...
That's DV, isn't it?
(domestic violence)
"Client
Mizutani Yukino"
I... might be killed by him.
Eh?!
"She's a client of Dad's, Mizutani Yukino-san."
"She's been receiving DV and being stalked
by her lover, Kubo Shunsuke."
"She had made an appointment with Dad
to consult with him over a video chat line."
"Even so..."
"...since he suddenly decided to go see
the Idol Okino Yoko-san's concert instead..."
"...I ended up going to the video chat."
What should I do about this?
I think he's watching me from somewhere.
I'm too scared to leave this apartment.
And this is why you were
video chatting with my Dad, isn't it?
Truth is, I live in the neighborhood.
Beika Apartments, room 301.
Ah, there.
I've had a bad feeling all of today.
He's come! It's Kubo!
Mizutani-san, you absolutely mustn't leave.
I'll report this to the police.
Don't! If you do that, I don't know what
revenge he'll take against me.
Then, what should we do?
Mizutani-san!
You mustn't leave there!
Stop!
You thought you could run away, huh?
Mizutani-san!
Mizutani-san!?
Kyaa! Save me!
Mizutani-san, are you okay?!
It couldn't be...
Hello, Shin'ichi?
There's been an incident.
Come to the Beika Apartments right away.
"Stop!"
"You thought you could run away, huh?"
"Don't! Don't come near me!"
"Stop!"
"Beika Apartments"
Ah, I'm sorry!
Mizutani-san!
Mizutani-san?
Mizutani-san...
"Beika Apartments"
When you were video chatting
with Mizutani Yukino-san...
...this man "Kubo" attacked her?
What does Kubo look like?
Well, um... thing is...
He never appeared on-screen.
You didn't see him?
Then you didn't see either
the criminal's face nor what happened?
But I heard her screaming, "Kubo-san, don't!"
I found this discarded in the trash.
Ah! That's the one!
He must be Kubo!
Huh? But you said
you didn't see him, didn't you?
I bumped into this man down
at the entrance hallway.
"I'm sorry!"
Mizutani-san told me how he had
used violence on her many times.
Maybe he's even killed her!
We can't conclude that is a
murder incident from just a few bloodstains.
No...
This was just a couple's dispute, wasn't it?
Shin'ichi! Say something!
Was she really chatting to you from here?
Eh? What do you mean?
The chat software hasn't been started.
If she had been chatting with Ran
when she was attacked...
...it should still be showing the Internet cafe
you left to come here.
I see.
Mizutani-san was definitely in this room!
These are the red curtains
I saw behind Mizutani-san.
I'm not mistaken!
Ran.
At the time you bumped into this Kubo,
was there anyone else around?
No, he was alone.
If it's as Ran says,
and that Kubo-san attacked Mizutani-san here...
...then she would most likely still be
somewhere here in this apartment building.
She would most likely still be
This incident occurred at 8:16.
"Mizutani-san!"
"Kyaa! Save me!"
Ran arrived here at 8:31.
The time in-between was only 15 minutes.
Even if Mizutani-san is a small person...
...for a murderer to forcibly tie her up
and take her away in just 15 minutes...
...the distance he would be able
to take her would be limited.
What's more, the only person who exited the
apartment complex during that time was that man.
If he had attempted to move
Mizutani-san in that condition...
...he would have been captured on
the surveillance video.
Please rescue Mizutani-san!
It may already be too late.
Detective Sato!
- Check every room in the complex.
- Yes!
Detective Sato...
"Still..."
"...Mizutani Yukino-san
was nowhere to be found."
"And then, 6 hours later..."
"...the case took an entirely
different direction."
"Saitama Weekly Apartments"
"Mizutani Yukino-san's body..."
"...was found in the room of
a weekly apartment in Saitama."
"Stop, Kubo-san!"
"Save me!"
Mizutani-san...
Around 2:00am...
...the Manager was making his rounds and,
seeing the door was open, discovered the corpse.
From the condition of the corpse, the estimated
time of death was between 8:00pm to 8:30pm.
That was the time when
Mizutani-san and I were chatting!
The cause of death was a sharp knife stuck
into her abdomen, causing excessive bleeding.
On the rug there are massive bloodstains.
Therefore the local Saitama police concluded
she had been stabbed to death here.
She was killed here?!
That couldn't be!
Mizutani-san was chatting with me
from her Beika Apartment, after all!
Ran.
Ah! Right, right,
this was where Mizutani-san was.
This is... from over here.
Eh?
This apartment has been arranged with...
...the same background trick as the one
over at the Beika Apartments during your chat.
What is this about?
In other words, we don't really know...
...which apartment Mizutani-san
was chatting from, the Beika Apartment...
...or here from the Saitama apartment.
But, judging from the situation here...
...it's right to think she was
killed here, isn't it?
The results of the investigation prove the blood
in these stains was from Mizutani Yukino-san.
"Stop!"
If she was in this apartment...
...then the line that Kubo-san
is the murderer disappears.
Why?!
She was screaming, "Stop it, Kubo-san!"
The distance from this apartment in Saitama
to the one in Beika is approximately 120 km.
It takes 3 hours to drive here.
To get here, where Mizutani-san was killed...
...to the Beika Apartments hallway where
Ran bumped into him only 15 minutes later...
...would be physically impossible.
If Kubo-san isn't the murderer...
Then did I hear it wrong?
Detective Sato!
We've discovered the victim's passport
and an airline boarding pass for today.
Thank you.
It's for Singapore, taking off at 6:25.
It's a one-way ticket.
She was thinking of getting away from
Kubo-san and making a fresh start in life.
Kudo-kun, is something bothering you?
Even if she was here hiding out from Kubo-san
until she could run off to a foreign country...
...why would she decorate this apartment
to match the one in the Beika Apartment complex?
When did she start renting this apartment?
According to the manager, Mizutani Yukino-san
booked it a week ago over the Internet.
An Internet reservation...
A week ago...
That's right!
I found this at home.
Here.
This is...
Ah, this cabbage is really cheap, isn't it?
Not that!
This!
"July 20th, phone consultation with Mizutani Yukino.
Stalker and DV victim."
"July 24th. Talked for 1 hour
by video chat from 9:30 pm."
"July 24th. 7:00pm, said she was afraid
of Kubo and cried. Cried during the video chat."
"Not being able to hold her
by the shoulders is irritating."
"Our next video chat
will be at 8:00 pm on the 27th."
This are Detective Mori's memos, aren't they?
The first time she and Ran's old man
had a consultations was on July 20th.
That was exactly one week ago.
I wonder what detective work she
asked Ran's father do in the first place?
Yukino!
- It's Kubo...
- Yukino!
Please stop!
Yukino is...
Has she really been killed?
Who on earth would do that...
Kubo Kensuke-san?
You and Mizutani Yukino-san were
talking about separating, weren't you?
"Yukino's Lover - Kubo Kensuke"
Are you suspicious of me?
I loved her!
You're lying!
You used violence against her, didn't you?
It looked like her face was injured and I also heard
her painful screams of "Please don't, please don't!"
I'm not lying!
I'm the victim.
She was originally in charge of
my brokerage firm...
...but she took my money away
by deception.
You'll know if you check into it...
Liar!
She also said you were stalking her.
You knowing about this Weekly Apartment
itself is evidence enough that you're a stalker!
It's true I was stalking Yukino.
"What should I do about this?"
It was because 60 million yen had
disappeared from my bank account.
So I looked for her in order
to get it back somehow.
I also knew about the existence of
this apartment 5 days ago.
At half past 8 this evening...
...you were in the Beika Apartment
complex, weren't you?
What were you doing?
I told you; I went to talk to her
about the money.
I thought if she apologized...
...I'd forgive her.
I really did love her.
Did you meet with Mizutani-san?
She wasn't in.
So when I had no choice but to go home,
that's when I bumped into this girl in the hallway.
You're lying.
You killed her!
You'd know best that it would
have been impossible for me to kill her!
It was... ESP!
I'm sure you could move her
in an instant with ESP, couldn't you!?
What are you talking about?
But...
Can you say there was another man
whom Mizutani Yukino-san was seeing?
There might have been.
You mean a love-triangle?
Why do you think that?
After all, she was beautiful...
...and now that the line
to Kubo-san has disappeared...
...isn't it natural to consider the possibility she'd
have another man bearing a grudge against her?
Another man, huh?
Another...
It originally occurred
at totally different place!
Huh? Have you figured it out?
Shin'ichi? Tell us.
There is only one truth.
That is...
...a love triangle.
Huh? What's that?
Who's the criminal?
The criminal is...
Kubo-san, please go home.
Where's your home?
Matoiwa, but...
That's about 2 hours away, isn't it?
Please take him home by police car.
Shin'ichi!
This guy's definitely the killer!
What do you mean the truth
is about a love triangle?
This doesn't consist of just two of them.
Eh? What's that?
Tell me how that's connected
to this incident! Shin'ichi!
"Incoming Video Chat call from Shin'ichi Kudo"
I'm sorry.
I forgot to ask you something.
Is it okay to talk about it using video chat?
Well truth is, this came out.
It's a fingerprint from the crime scene.
They said they were luckily able to pull this
from off of Mizutani Yukino-san's clothes.
And, sorry to trouble you...
...but I wanted to confirm with you
that this isn't your fingerprint.
After that, there was something like
a character written on the rug.
Would you have some idea of
Mizutani Yukino-san's way of writing?
I've taken a photo of it,
so if you could take a look at it.
I think the detectives are
on their way out there now.
Let's see...
Could you wait there for 2 hours?
All right. I'll be waiting.
Kubo-san.
It seems we arrived
a little sooner than you thought.
Ho... how...
We did it the same way you did.
The criminal is you, isn't it,
Kubo Kensuke-san?
What do you mean?
The color of the doors at those
Weekly Apartments in Saitama are an olive green.
So, when you saw me standing in front of
an olive green door...
...Kubo-san, you simply believed I was still at
those Weekly Apartments in Saitama.
But...
Truth is, I was nearby.
Colors and shapes make
the greatest impression on the brain...
It remembers those sorts of things.
Kudo-kun, please explain this clearly.
If Mizutani-san had been killed
in those Weekly Apartments in Saitama...
...it would have been impossible for Kubo-san...
...who was at the Beika Apartments,
to have committed the crime in those 15 minutes.
It takes 3 hours by car to get to the Weekly
Apartments from the Beika Apartments, doesn't it?
In truth, she was killed within a range of
15 minutes from the Beika Apartments.
In other words...
Like this.
Oh, Ran-chan!
Where are you right now?
The Weekly Apartments in Saitama?
Or else at the Beika Apartment complex?
I'm at neither.
Eh?
There was a third apartment.
That was where you killed her,
wasn't it, Kubo-san?
Huh?
This has the same interior?
Yes.
In other words, three apartments that
would appear the same on the video chat...
"Beika Apartments
Saitama Weekly Apartments - Third Apartment"
You could say there were 3 different places.
Why would he do such a thing?
It's true that Mizutani-san
cheated you out of the 60 million yen.
Furthermore, she planned to make it seem
as if you had murdered her...
...and would then run off to a foreign country.
She was a terrible woman.
In order to have someone who could testify to
her situation and that she had been killed...
...she got in touch with
Ran's father by video chat.
The main point though is that Ran's father
went to a live concert instead.
Then, what were those screams I heard?
This.
"Stop!"
Most likely this recording...
Was a recording from the time when...
...Kubo-san stormed over to
Mizutani-san's apartment to complain, wasn't it?
"This is all a misunderstanding."
"Stop."
"Stop it!"
"You thought you could run away from me?"
"You thought you'd made a fool of me!"
What she then played back to Ran was...
"Mizutani-san!"
"You shouldn't go out!"
"Stop!"
"You thought you'd make a fool of me!?"
"You deceived me! You rascal!"
"Mizutani-san!"
She made Ran believe she was being
attacked during the video chat.
I was tricked by that woman!
Then, there wasn't any DV?
But Shin'ichi, how did you figure out
she was putting on an act?
Ah, that was from the gauze.
"It looked like she'd been hurt on her face."
But, after she was killed,
there wasn't a wound on her face.
I was totally tricked.
Yeah.
The blood and the traces of a fight we found
at the Beika Apartments when we raced over...
Those were things she had
prepared beforehand.
But, since you were keeping a watch on her...
...you saw everything she had done
to try and camouflage her work...
...at the third apartment while
on the video chat with Ran.
Since she didn't know that
you had found her out...
...Ran went to the
Beika Apartments as planned...
"3rd Apartment"
At that point, she headed for the airport.
But...
"It's better to return the money, right?
Go ahead and take it!"
"'Cause without money,
you can't get a woman, can you..."
She was killed by you.
If she was killed here, why did we find her
at those Weekly Apartments in Saitama?
Why did Mizutani-san even rent
that apartment for?
It wasn't Mizutani-san who rented
that Weekly Apartment.
It was you.
You rented that apartment in Mizutani-san's
name because you knew of her plan to escape.
You used the anonymity of
the Internet, didn't you?
"Beika Apartment"
And, you gave the interior of that apartment...
"Saitama Apartment"
...the same setting as the Beika apartment one.
And, having killed Mizutani-san
in the 3rd apartment...
...Kubo-san then went over to
the Beika apartment.
Taking advantage of her prepared play...
...you rushed over to Beika Apartments
so you could bump into Ran.
Having made eye-witness testimony
as to being over there...
...Kubo-san returned to the Weekly Apartments
in Saitama bringing over the corpse and the PC.
Ah, by doing that...
...Kubo-san made it look as if Mizutani-san had been killed
during her video chat at the Saitama Weekly Apartments...
...and since he had been seen at the Beika Apartments,
it would have seemed impossible for him to have done it.
Yes!
Kubo-san had planned the perfect crime by taking
advantage of Mizutani-san's own escape plans.
Even though it was the perfect plan...
How were you able to find me out
from that apartment?
The rug.
The rug?
There was a great deal of blood
found soaked into...
...the rug laid out in the
Saitama Weekly Apartment.
But, though it seemed there should be blood on
the walls and floor, it was only on the rug itself.
When I considered the reasons for that,
there was only one.
That the crime had been performed at
some other place.
But...
...there's no evidence that a body
had been carried away from here...
That's because he didn't carry away
just the corpse.
He also took away the rug.
The one from this 3rd apartment.
From this portion here...
...when connecting it to the rug,
I could see the character "Ku."
Mizutani-san's dying message
was that you were her killer.
Damn!
Even though I had the perfect plan.
Even if you did realize the existence
of a 3rd apartment...
...you shouldn't have been able
to sniff out this apartment!
How did you find out about this apartment?
Easy.
She was killed at 8:16pm.
Ran witnessed you at
Beika Apartments at 8:31pm.
When I hypothesized you had killed
Mizutani-san in some 3rd apartment...
...I knew that 3rd apartment had to be within a
range of 15 minutes from the Beika Apartments.
Furthermore, having to deal with the corpse...
"Heavy!"
"Hey, hey, ow!"
When I verified the time it would take you
to set up your alibi...
...it was 3 hours, 10 minutes.
In other words, because the body
was found 6 hours later...
...the time left for you to move it
was 2 hours and 50 minutes.
When you take a circle of 2 hours 50 minutes
from the Weekly Apartments in Saitama...
...and another circle of 15 minutes from
the Beika Apartments...
...this is where they intersected.
The 3rd apartment had to be in the area
where those two circles intersected.
Moreover, when you zoom in on that area...
Due to a pond being in there...
"Third Apartment"
...there was only this one apartment complex.
I'm not the bad one!
Not at all!
The bad one was that woman!
I loved that woman
from the bottom of my heart!
I didn't intend to kill her!
You say you knew of her betrayal...
...and that you committed your crime
in an unexpected fit of passion.
Kubo-san...
Even so, you calmly planned out
a perfect crime...
...and even meticulously prepared for it
by renting that Weekly Apartment.
Overflowing with malice, you killed her.
You can't talk your way out of that.
Ahh...
I was just tricked and used by
the both of them.
Ran!
Save me, Shin'ichi! Shin...
"Video Chat"
Ran!
"Unknown Caller"
"Time Difference Trick
Hidden in the Elevator"
"Will Shin'ichi Confess to Ran at Last?!"